ほしか
むった
(星加)どうした？六太君｡
What is it, Mutta?
なんば
(南波六太)星加さん…ﾋｭｰｽﾄﾝに
頼めませんか？
Hoshika...
Can you relay a message to Houston?
何を？
What?
バディたちの
ビートルの行き先を➡
Can you ask them to have Buddy, in the Beetle,
もっとこっちの方に
変更してもらえないか｡
head toward this direction?
(職員)でも南波君 その位置じゃ
２人が落ちた位置から➡
But, Nanba...
That's almost twenty kilometers from where they fell.
２０ｋｍくらい離れているよ｡
何でそこに？
Why should they head there?
ひびと
日々人は多分…
じっとしていないからです｡
Hibito is probably
on the move.
ﾎﾞｲｽﾗｲﾀｰの会話
(ﾀﾞﾐｱﾝ)体温調節システムが
故障したらしい｡➡
My temperature regulation system is busted.
じゅんかん
水の循環が悪くなってるようで…
体が凍りそうに寒い｡➡
I'm not getting enough water...
My body is freezing.
ﾌﾞﾗｲｱﾝとの話を思い出してたんだ｡
わかるだろ ヒビト｡
I was remembering what Brian told us...
I know you understand, Hibito.
If two astronauts conducting an EVA have an accident,
(ﾌﾞﾗｲｱﾝ)２人での船外活動中
何らかの事故により➡
and one astronaut cannot be saved,
仲間の命が助からないと
判断できる時➡
せいかん
これを切り捨て 自分の生還を
第一に考えること｡
you must abandon that astronaut, to prioritize your own survival.
ﾎﾞｲｽﾗｲﾀｰの会話
俺を置いて行ってくれ…｡
Leave me behind.
ﾎﾞｲｽﾗｲﾀｰの会話
(南波日々人)俺はさあ ダミアン➡
Guess what, Damian?
あんたの命を助けられると
判断してるよ｡
I'm saying that I can save your life.
《スピードを上げていこう｡➡
We can go a little faster.
I need to get Damian under the sun and warm him up.
ダミアンを早く日なたに出して
体を温めないと》
Forty minutes of oxygen left.
《酸素残量 あと４０分！》
ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…｡
《酸素残量 あと２０分！》
Twenty minutes of oxygen left.
I-It's over...
《だ だめだ…寒い…》
I'm so cold.
ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…｡
あっ！うわ～っ‼
Space Brothers
I can no longer remember
what I tried to forget
When I peeked through the telescope
I realized that our world is tiny
It was a picture of infinity
It's not a one-time thing
We'll walk together
Once we've passed the clouds,
we will hold the world between our fingers
and keep what we lost in mind
#42 Hibito's Choice
It'll be another thirty minutes before we reach the buggy crash site.
(ﾌﾚﾃﾞｨ)バギーの落下地点まで
あと３０分程度だ｡➡
着いたら俺は下に降りる｡バディは
ウインチで引き上げてくれ｡
Once we arrive, I'll head down.
Buddy, you use the crane to pull us up.
Yeah.
もし その場にいなかったら…
やっかい
厄介だな｡
It could get ugly if they're not there.
いるさ｡移動すれば危険が増すこと
ぐらい ２人はわかっているよ｡
They'll be there.
I'm sure they know it's dangerous to move about.
(ﾌﾚﾃﾞｨ)それとも何だ？➡
Or what?
謎の発光体から 全身銀色の
頭でっかちが現れて➡
Do you think silver creatures,
with huge foreheads, popped out of the flash,
and those two got scared and ran away?
２人はビビッて逃げてる可能性が
あるとか考えていたのか？
いや さすがに｢銀色｣までは
考えてなかったけど｡
No.
I wasn't expecting them to be silver.
Come on...
あのな…そう心配するな バディ｡
Don't worry about it too much, Buddy.
もし移動してるなら それとわかる
サインを出してきてるはずだろ｡
If they've moved, they'll give us a sign to let us know.
ああ…そうだな｡
Yeah, you're right.
We have one more shot.
もう一発残ってるんだ｡
日々人かダミアン どちらかの
しょうめいだん
照明弾がまだ打ち上がってない｡
One of them hasn't used his flare yet.
They started at the point where the first flare was launched.
最後に照明が打ち上がった場所が
２人の居場所…➡
移動してるなら
その先で打ち上げてくるはず…➡
If they've moved, they should fire the second one.
けんかい
というのがヒューストンの見解だ｡
That was Houston's call.
ひとまず我々も フレディたちの
到着を待つしかない｡
So we'll have to wait for Freddy and Buddy to get there.
Let's all pray that they're safe.
２人の無事をみんなで祈ろう｡
I'm not gonna pray, Hibito.
《俺は祈らねえぞ 日々人…
祈らねえ 祈らねえ》
That's not gonna happen...
(南波母)⦅えっ？日々人が!?➡
What? Hibito?
はい…ええ ええ…
わ わかりました⦆
Yes.
Yeah.
Yeah...
I-I understand.
⦅どうしましょう
どうしましょう…⦆
Oh, no.
Oh, no...
Over the years, the family's had to worry about you a lot...
《お前は昔からいつも 家族に
さんざん心配かけといて…》
《何もなかったかのように
普通に帰ってきやがる》
And then you'd come home, acting like nothing had happened.
《どうせ今回もそうだろ｡
知ってんだぜ チキショー》
It's probably the same this time.
I know you too well.
I'm not worried,
《俺は心配してねえから
祈らねえ…》
so I won't pray.
ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…｡
Sorry, Damian...
ﾎﾞｲｽﾗｲﾀｰの会話
悪いな ダミアン
また滑っちまった…ダミアン？
I took another tumble.
Damian?
ﾎﾞｲｽﾗｲﾀｰの会話
寒い…ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…
寒…い｡
I'm cold...
So cold.
Damn.
《くそっ このままじゃ 日なたに
上がる前にダミアンは…》
At this rate...
Damian won't make it to the sunlight...
こどう
今すぐ熱を作らねえと…
どうすりゃいい？
I need to generate some heat now.
What should I do?
熱…熱…熱…｡
Heat... Heat... Heat...
《マークライトならあるけど…➡
I've got a marker light,
こんなもん点けたって
温度にならねえし…➡
but this won't provide any heat.
Damn, isn't there anything else?
くそっ！何かねえのか！》
《照明弾…➡
A flare...
こいつが発光した時の熱は
使えそうだが…➡
I can use the heat it generates.
これを使ってしまったら…》
But if I use this...
《フレディたちに 俺たちの
居場所を伝えられなくなる》
We won't be able to signal Freddy and Buddy with our location.
I don't have time to think.
《迷ってるヒマはねえな》
⦅パパが月に行って
もし帰ってこなかったらね➡
And if Daddy goes to the moon and doesn't come back,
that means he's on the moon, too.
そん時は
パパも月にいるんだって｡➡
I'll just have to look at the moon to see him, so there's nothing to worry about.
月を見れば そこにパパがいるん
だから 何も心配するなってさ｡➡
でも…そうなったらヤダなあ⦆
But I don't want that to happen...
ブライアンが バギーの落下地点に
到着しました｡➡
Brian has arrived at the buggy crash site.
We've confirmed that the tire tracks end at the edge of the ravine.
ふち
わだちが谷の縁で切れてるのが
確認できます｡
(ｸﾗｳﾄﾞ)谷の中を映せるか？
(ﾈｯﾄﾜｰｸ管制官)やってみます｡
Can you see into the ravine?
I'll give it a try.
It's completely dark...
(ﾈｯﾄﾜｰｸ管制官)真っ暗ですね｡
(ｸﾗｳﾄﾞ)何も見えんな｡
We can't see a thing.
Claude?
あずま
(吾妻)クラウドさん｡
What is it?
Okay...
《よし…》
はへん
《この熱くなった破片や石を
ダミアンの宇宙服に固定して➡
If I place the heated scraps and rubble on Damian's spacesuit,
上からまた
だんねつ
断熱シートでくるめば➡
then wrap the insulation sheet around him,
凍りついた循環水を
溶かせるかもしれない》
the water in his suit may start to thaw.
(ﾀﾞﾐｱﾝ)《あ…何だ？》
What?
I feel...
《少し…温かい…》
a little warmer.
ハァ ハァ ハァ ハァ…｡
We're almost there, Damian!
《もうすぐだ ダミアン！》
ヒューストン｡こちら
フレディとバディだ｡➡
Houston, this is Freddy and Buddy.
バギーの落下地点に到達した｡
これより救出作業に とりかかる｡
We've arrived at the buggy crash site.
We'll begin the rescue operation now.
ヒューストン！聞こえるか？
Houston, do you read me?
This is Hibito.
こちら 日々人｡
ヒューストン！
Houston!
《ここまで来ても まだ
つながらないか…》
I'm still not in range?
《でも あと少し！》
But we're almost there.
見えるか ダミアン｡
See that, Damian?
It's brilliant.
まぶしいね｡
帰ってきたぞ ダミアン｡
We made it out, Damian!
ダミアン…
生きててくれよ｡
Damian,
don't die on me.
《日なたは110度以上ある｡太陽に
さらすのは １分程度でいい｡➡
The sunlight is over 110 degrees Celsius.
I only need to expose him for a minute.
それで充分 循環水は温まる｡
これは賭けだな 断熱シートを➡
That should be enough to warm up his suit.
This is risky...
If I don't cover Damian fast enough,
かぶせるタイミングが遅れたら…
逆に ダミアンに➡
he'll be boiled alive in his suit.
熱湯を ぶっかけるようなもんだ》
よし｡
Okay.
ヒューストン ヒューストン
応答してくれ！
Houston, Houston. Do you read me?
Houston, this is Hibito.
ヒューストン こちら日々人｡
ヒューストン！
Houston!
フレディ！バディ！こちら日々人｡
カレン！リンダ！応答してくれ！
Freddy! Buddy!
This is Hibito!
Karen! Linda!
Do you read me?
《クソッ…クソッ》
Damn...
Damn!
宇宙服のアラート信号を
とらえました！➡
We've received a spacesuit alert!
ダミアンはヒビトと一緒にいます｡
通話は出来ませんが➡
Damian is with Hibito.
We're unable to communicate, but they've both made it out of the ravine.
２人とも 谷を
脱出したようです！
Whew, that's a relief...
ふぅ～っ よかった｡
場所は？
Where are they?
バギーが落ちた地点から 谷を背に
３時の方角へ２０キロ地点です｡
Twenty kilometers, in a three o'clock direction from the moon.
２０キロ!?
ＪＡＸＡが指定してたポイントだ｡
Twenty kilometers?
That's the point JAXA indicated.
フレディ達に伝えて
すぐ向かわせろ｡
Tell Freddy and Buddy to head there immediately.
了解｡
Roger that.
(ﾒｶﾞﾈ管制官)た 大変だ！
どうした？
Th-This is terrible!
What's wrong?
ヒ ヒビトの酸素が…
あと １０分も もちません！
H-Hibito has...
under ten minutes of oxygen left!
了解した｡すぐに向かう！➡
Roger that! We're on our way!
聞いてたな バディ｡
ビートルを出せ！
Did you hear that, Buddy?
Start up Beetle!
ＯＫ！つかまれ！
Okay! Hang on tight!
出してくれ！
Go!
《クソッ こいつのスピードじゃ
ヒビト達の とこまで➡
Damn it...
In this thing, it'll take twenty minutes to catch Hibito!
２０分以上 かかっちまう｡
それじゃ 間に合わねえ！》
We won't make it in time!
ﾎﾞｲｽﾗｲﾀｰの会話
ヒビト…｡
Hibito...
ﾎﾞｲｽﾗｲﾀｰの会話
助けが来るまで ここにいろ
ダミアン｡ギブソンの➡
Wait here until help comes, Damian.
Gibson should shade you from any sudden heat spikes.
影にいれば 急激な
温度上昇も弱まるよ｡
ﾎﾞｲｽﾗｲﾀｰの会話
どこへ 行くんだ…ヒビト｡
Where are you going, Hibito?
ﾎﾞｲｽﾗｲﾀｰの会話
前からさ 一度でいいから
やってみたかったんだよな｡
There's something I've always wanted to try.
ﾎﾞｲｽﾗｲﾀｰの会話
月面を ひとりで散歩｡
Taking a walk on the moon by myself.
ﾎﾞｲｽﾗｲﾀｰの会話
ヒビト…ヒビト！
Hibito... Hibito...
《酸素残量…８分｡
８分か クソッ！》
Eight minutes of oxygen left...
Eight minutes, huh?
Damn!
《どうせ死ぬなら また
あの谷に落っこちて…｡➡
If I have to die, I'd rather go back in the ravine
満天の星でも見ながらが いいな｡
そうするか》
and look up at the stars.
Might as well.
Freddy and Buddy will have to pull my body out of the ravine.
《俺の死体を引き上げるのに
フレデｨ達に面倒かけちまうが➡
まあ許してくれよ
それくらい…》
But they'll probably forgive me for that much.
あ…あれは？
Th-That's...
《変更だ》
Change in plans.
《どうせ死ぬなら 謎の光の正体を
知ってからがいい》
If I'm gonna die,
I wanna know where that flash is coming from first.
ハァ ハァ…｡
ブライ…アン…｡
Brian...
The stones out in the fields
are worn down by their daily existence and disappear
That's their trial
When will we be able to resist fate?
Before you lose all hope
and say that we can't win against gravity
go without stopping
past the goal line
You have such strong convictions
Leave your footprints on this Earth
Maybe their tiny length will cause a miracle in the end
Give us a magnificent jump
Run now and do it
Jump past all you see overhead
This is your stride
(管制官)＜日々人君の酸素残量
あと３分です＞
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#43 Brian
Hibito's down to three minutes of oxygen.
(原田)＜星加さん｡六太さんに
知らせなくても？＞
Hoshika, shouldn't we tell Mutta?
＜通話ができるなら ともかく➡
Perhaps if there were a way to communicate.
ただ モニターの酸素数値が
減っていくのを見せたくない＞
But I don't want him to have to stare at a monitor while his brother runs out of oxygen.
Damn it! We're not gonna make it in time!
＜クソッ 絶対に間に合わねえ！➡
Hibito's gonna...
ヒビトが…
ヒビトが死んじまう！＞
Hibito's gonna die!
Oxygen supply exhausted.
(管制官)＜酸素供給 停止｡➡
宇宙服内の酸素は
２０％から下降中！＞
Oxygen within spacesuit falling under twenty percent!
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"Brian"
＜悪い｡悪い…ムッちゃん＞
Sorry...
Sorry, Mu.
パンパカパーン！
This Week's Space Photo
A mysterious capsule in the middle of the snow?
This week's space photo!
今週の宇宙写真です！
なんじゃこら！
What's that?